ROBERT FARRIS

OXFORD, MISSISSIPPI PHONE: (907) 907-9506 LINKEDIN: HTTPS://www.linkedin.com/in/bigmrrob
Website: RBFDevelopment.com | E-mail: rbfarris@go.olemiss.edu

An ambitious computer science undergraduate with a proven track record for providing reliable technical expertise, project management, and program delivery. An innovator who excels in the challenge of accurate solutions for difficult situations in software systems design, software development, interaction design, machine learning, and computational mathematics. A well-rounded and reliable leader with outstanding interpersonal and communication skills, driven to analyze code and engineer well-researched, and cost-effective solutions to advance strategic business priorities and plans.

CORE SKILLS AND KNOWLEDGE

Program and Project Management Cross Functional Leadership Planning Agile Management Methodologies HTML5/SASS/PHP/JavaScript Java (Swing and FX), Python, C# Unity Development AR/VR/Mixed Reality Development React/Angular/Bootstrap Change Management and Scheduling Process Improvement and Databases Solutions Architecture and Delivery Application Design and Development Machine Learning/Advanced Math Basic 3D/Low-poly modeling UI/UX Design OpenGL/QML Web Design Tools, Programming Web Development and Design Software Development Lifecycle Bug Fixing and Troubleshooting HTML5, SASS, Bootstrap, Angular Basic AR, VR, MR Development C#/F#/C++/AR Foundations Communication and Reporting

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF MISSISSIPPI, OXFORD, MISSISSIPPI

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE - COMPUTER SCIENCE

MAY 2020

EXPERIENCE

RBF DEVELOPMENT, OXFORD, MISSISSIPPI

2014 - PRESENT

FREELANCE WEB DEVELOPER

- > Designed and developed client-focused and responsive web applications with HTML, CSS, WordPress, and jQuery
- > Collaborated with clients on frontend development, optimizing UX, SEO, sales, brand positioning, and metrics
- > Assisted clients in various tasks such as hardware repair and other computer software development projects
- Conducted mission-critical code fixes throughout all layers of large-scale JavaScript and JQuery web applications
- Completed end-to-end testing and unit tests to ensure applications performance, quality, and responsiveness
- > Liaised with clients through project milestone to discuss and negotiate design changes to next development stages
- > Developed sites for ecommerce businesses in WordPress, React Applications, and Bootstrap with Custom CMS 505 FITNESS GROUP
 - > Built run tracking data application in MS Angular with user authentication and login on Firebase database system
 - > Assessed fitness training requirements in order to define application function and client database expectations

UNITY VR APPLICATION

- ➤ Built basic Unity games using C# to be ported to mobile apps and VR headsets with physical environment mapping DOORDASH AND UBER EATS REPLICA APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT (TEAM OF 7 PROJECT)
- > Create user portals for restaurants, drivers, and customers for orders and estimated delivery times from location
 DEFENSE COMPANY COVID19 WEB APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT (MOST RECENT PROJECT)
 - Support Covid19 application for Defense company using bootstrap website with software development company

UNIVERSITY OF MISSISSIPPI, OXFORD, MISSISSIPPI

DECEMBER 2019 – JUNE 2020

INTERNSHIP – OPEN GL, QML, C++ ON FABRIC DEFECT DETECTION SYSTEMS

> Responsible for building fabric fault detection system in OpenGL to interface with cameras using OpenCV analysis

UNIVERSITY OF MISSISSIPPI, OXFORD, MISSISSIPPI

March 2016 - Present

OLE MISS IT DESK AND LAB SUPPLEMENTAL INSTRUCTOR

- > Supported IT department to troubleshoot basic student needs, monitored programming labs for Java development
- Provided helpdesk support for technical issues to minimize data loss, meet deadlines, and achieve user needs

ROBERT FARRIS PAGE 1